A Guide to the Triplett, Irvin, and Wilkins Business Records, 1918-1938
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Triplett, Irvin, and Wilkins Business Records, 1906-1938
Library of Virginia
1109330-332, 1109334, 1109365, 1109376, 1109400, 1109423, 1109428-429, 1109432, 1109436-437, 1109440-441, 1130485-486, 1130535-536
19 vol. (5503 p.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a transfer of court papers from Shenandoah County.
Historical Information
Triplett, Irvin, and Wilkins was a wholesale dealer in tobacco, confections, salt, and feed and a retailer of farm supplies during the early twentieth century in Shenandoah County, Virginia. The company had businesses in the towns of Woodstock and Edinburg.
Volumes were used as exhibits in an unidentified suit heard in Shenandoah County Circuit Court.
Scope and Content
The business records of Triplett, Irvin, and Wilkins consist of two daybooks, five ledgers, ten cashbooks, and two invoice record books.
Two daybooks, 1918, 1920-1921, records transactions as they occurred on a daily basis from February-November 1918. Information found in each entry includes name of customer, items purchased, quantity of items purchased, form of payment, amount owed, and amount paid. Merchandise sold include seed, corn, salt, rock salt, hay, oil, livestock feed, coal, wire fence, fertilizer, and cement. Payments made by check, cash, credit, labor, and barter of items such as corn, bark, and harrow teeth. Page numbers found in daybooks correspond with page numbers found in Ledger, 1918-1921. Daybook, 1920-1921, also includes miscellaneous information dated 1936-1938.
Ledger, 1918-1921, records the individual accounts of customers. Each account lists transactions in chronological order. Information found in each entry include date of transaction, amount owed, form of payment, and amount paid. Ledger does not list items purchased, rather it uses the general term "merchandise." The ledger also includes the company's controlling accounts such as expense account and phosphate account. Page numbers found in entries correspond with page numbers found in daybooks.
Ledger, 1926-1935, records in alphabetical order by surname the individual accounts of customers. Each account records name of customer and place of residence and lists transactions in chronological order. Information found in each entry include date of transaction, items purchased, form of payment, amount owed, and amount paid.
Ten cashbooks, 1916-1932, records in chronological order the company's receipts and disbursements. Information found in volume was divided into sections. The first section on the left side of the volume records receipts from cash or check, the name of company or individual who wrote the check, amount received, and whether cash received was from sell of tobacco or sells made by warehouse. The right side of the volume records the cash paid by Triplett, Irvin, and Wilkins for expenses, name of expense, and cash paid out by the stores in Woodstock and Edinburg.
Ledger, 1934-1935, records in chronological order the daily transactions of Triplett, Irvin, and Wilkins. Information found in the ledger is divided into the following categories: a record of daily purchases, a record of daily sales, a record of daily cash receipts, bank deposits, and a record of cash payments. Entries include the names of individuals and companies with whom the company did business and expenses paid such as freight, wages, postage, gas, and ice.
Ledger, 1935-1938, records the individual accounts of customers. Each account lists name of customer and transactions in chronological order. Information found in each entry include date of transaction, items purchased, form of payment, amount owed, and amount paid. The volume also records the amount of money collected and paid by Triplett, Irvin, and Wilkins from 1936 to 1938. Information found in the entries includes date of transaction, total daily sales, money deposited in the bank, and expenses paid.
Two invoice record books, 1916-1921, 1926-1938, records the individual accounts of customers. Each account lists transactions in chronological order. Information found in each entry include date of invoice, invoice number of payment, amount owed, cash discount, amount of discount, and date paid. The volume includes additional miscellaneous information.
Access Terms
Triplett, Irvin, and Wilkins (Shenandoah County, Va.); Agriculture--Economic aspects--Virginia--Shenandoah County.; Barter--Virginia--Shenandoah County.; Farm supplies--Virginia--Shenandoah County.; Retail trade--Virginia--Shenandoah County.; Tobacco trade--Virginia--Shenandoah County.; Shenandoah County (Va.)--History--20th century.; Business records--Virginia--Shenandoah County.; Cashbooks--Virginia--Shenandoah County.; Daybooks--Virginia--Shenandoah County.; Invoices--Virginia--Shenandoah County.; Ledgers (account books)--Virginia--Shenandoah County.; Local government records--Virginia--Shenandoah County.
Contents List
- Daybook, 1918, 1130535
- Daybook, 1920-1921, 1938, 1130536
- Invoice record book, 1916-1921, 1109376
- Invoice record book, 1926-1938, 1109400
- Ledger, 1906-1935, 1109441
- Ledger, 1918-1921, 1109436
- Ledger, 1926-1935, 1109365
- Ledger, 1934-1935, 1130486
- Ledger, 1935-1938, 1130485
- Cashbook, 1916-1918, 1109334
- Cashbook, 1918-1920, 1109423
- Cashbook, 1920-1921, 1109331
- Cashbook, 1922-1923, 1109440
- Cashbook, 1923-1925, 1109332
- Cashbook, 1925-1926, 1109432
- Cashbook, 1926-1928, 1109428
- Cashbook, 1928-1929, 1109437
- Cashbook, 1929-1930, 1109330
- Cashbook, 1930-1932, 1109429